Hold it!
I didn't know who to expect, but I'm surprised to see Saber's Master.
You appear to have the will to fight, but that means nothing.
Without your precious Saber, you are worthless.
Hold on a second.
That guy's an acquaintance of mine.
Fancy meeting you in a place like this, E-mi-ya.
Allow me to introduce my new Servant.
A Winter's Day, the Form Wishes Take
He's way more awesome than Rider, right?
Now, why don't you beg for your life?
I might even consider sparing it.
Never!
Is that so?
In that case, go ahead and die, you bastard—
That's enough!
You, the Servant there...
If you move so much as a finger, it'll cost your Master his life!
T-Tohsaka...
You threatened him, rather than killing him outright,
because you determined that killing him would not stop me, correct?
That's right.
But even for you, losing your Master would have to be a serious blow.
Wh-What do you think you're doing?
The situation has changed, Shinji.
That girl will be a satisfactory vessel.
Oh, right...
How about this, Tohsaka?
Why not ditch Emiya and join forces with us?
I'm sure you know that Caster is amassing power.
Ryuudou Temple will be the altar this time.
If we do nothing, we'll be at a slight disadvantage—
No thanks, Shinji.
It makes no sense to follow someone who's just a flunky.
What did you say?
Kill them, Gilgamesh!
Kill both Emiya and Tohsaka!
No.
Unfortunately, we have run out of time.
If we tarry any longer, our prize will spoil.
Damn it!
You'll regret this, Tohsaka!
Don't think I'll make this offer again!
You heard him.
You have a good friend.
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
It wasn't your fault, Shirou.
There was nothing we could have done to save her.
Why did you do it?
You must have known you'd be killed
if you showed yourself to him.
So how could you take such a risk for that girl?
What's there to say?
I stepped in because I wanted to save her. That's all.
I always thought there was something off about you, but this clinches it.
Shirou, the way you live is seriously twisted.
Twisted?
That's right.
The way you value others more than yourself is wrong.
Listen, everyone has to look out for themselves first.
Yet here you are, always trying to help others.
Keeping that up for too long will break a person!
That isn't true.
In fact, I do what I do to avoid that.
No, you're already quite broken.
So, tell me.
What happened ten years ago?
Because I bet that's what made you so screwed up!
You're wrong, Tohsaka.
All that happened was that I was saved.
Saved?
Yeah. That's all there is to it.
Something wasn't taken from you in exchange for being saved?
No.
Kiritsugu saved me. That's all.
I didn't lose anything.
It's just...
He looked so happy.
I admired that look on his face.
When I was rescued, that was the only emotion I felt.
I wanted to become someone like him.
That's why...
I thought if that happened again,
I'd have to save every last person
to make up for all those I turned my back on the last time.
That's my only wish.
Because otherwise,
my being the sole survivor would be meaningless.
And I'm telling you that's messed up!
If he saved your life, you should treasure it!
After going through something so terrible,
if you don't enjoy the rest of your life, what's the point?!
Look...
Wishing only for other people's happiness is wrong!
That makes you no different from a machine!
Helping others is fine. Knock yourself out.
But do it for yourself!
Unless you live life for yourself,
you won't even know what happiness is!
Yeah.
I'm sure you're right, Tohsaka.
Then...
But it's okay.
I mean,
wanting to live your life to help others...
can't possibly be wrong.
Thanks, Tohsaka.
Honestly...
How can I say anything when you look at me like that?
Fine, whatever.
I guess it's up to me to think of something now.
Hey.
About that eighth Servant...
Gilgamesh.
He's a hero from ancient Mesopotamian myth, right?
A hero who's half-god, half-man.
King of Uruk,
seeker of eternal youth.
He's so powerful it's almost unfair.
And yet...
What is it?
He was definitely powerful,
but I didn't sense much of a power gap between Blondie and Berserker.
Is it just me?
No.
On his own, he's on par with Saber or Berserker,
or even less powerful.
The difference is his weaponry.
Each of the weapons he had was a Noble Phantasm in itself.
Or rather, I bet they're the actual weapons that the Noble Phantasms were based on.
Gilgamesh is the hero from the world's most ancient myth—
a king who's indulged in every luxury.
Then it makes sense that he has the origins of the myths—
the weapons on which Noble Phantasms were based.
Which means his Noble Phantasm
isn't one of the weapons themselves.
The treasury that housed all the valuables he amassed in life
is probably his Noble Phantasm.
In which case, it's no wonder that Berserker was no match for him.
If he has the archetypes of all Noble Phantasms,
all he has to do is pull out whatever
a given Heroic Spirit is weak against.
That guy's really going to be a problem.
But at the moment, Caster is the more pressing concern,
so we'll have to put him off for now.
True.
Just you two against her?
Come on, you know that won't work.
Fools.
Lancer!
We haven't met since that night, have we,
my two friends?
Shirou, get back!
Tohsaka, run!
I'll draw him off, so make a break for the forest!
No, I'll hold him off!
Keep your distance from him!
Wait a second...
It sounds like you didn't hear a word I said when I told you to put yourself first!
And I said that it's okay.
I've fought him before, so I'm better for the job.
He's a foot soldier! My ranged attacks are better against him!
That's my point!
You stay clear and cover me!
My spells aren't pinpoint accurate, you know!
If I did that, I'd blow you away along with him!
Don't bite my head off!
Why is it always overkill with you?
Wh-What was that, you jerk?
He's dangerous, so I want you to stay clear!
Finished already?
I'm in no rush, so feel free to get it out of your systems.
Hold on, now.
I have no intention of fighting you.
I couldn't bear to stand by and watch,
so I thought I'd presume to offer my aid.
What?
Did I mishear that?
That sounded a lot like you were offering to help us.
What? Is that so hard to understand?
You two alone are no match for Caster.
In light of that,
I'm willing to lend a hand.
Yes, that certainly is presumptuous, Lancer.
Is this your idea?
An order from my Master.
They wish to form a united front
until Caster's little army is beaten.
A valid reason.
But surely there must be better candidates than us.
The guy who beat Berserker?
He's no good.
We wouldn't get along.
I can't fault his strength, though.
That's a smart decision.
Was that also your Master's order?
No.
I chose you two out of personal preference.
You've nearly killed me twice so far.
Do you think I'll believe a word you say?
Of course.
The brains of this outfit is a fine, frank woman.
And with such a woman helping you,
you must be an eccentric softy yourself.
Meaning that you two are the best people to work with.
If you can't pick your job, you should at least pick your partner, right?
I've liked you ever since I first laid eyes on you.
You're beautiful, stubborn, and gutsy.
If I were to have a female Master,
I'd want her to be someone like you.
All right. I'm on board.
But if Emiya-kun says he can't trust you,
you can forget the whole thing.
You heard her.
What'll it be, kid?
Your character's being put to the test.
Fine.
But on one condition.
If you're willing to help us, we'll trust you.
But in return...
"In return" what?
You want me to tell you who my Master is?
No.
Just because we're on the same side,
don't try to make passes at Tohsaka.
Wha—
Oh, I see!
Right you are!
That's way more important than a little thing
like who my Master is, kid!
Is there something wrong with that?
Let me say it straight: you can't have Tohsaka.
Of course not.
In fact, I respect you more for that.
Good for you, missy.
The kid's smitten with you.
Wh-What are you babbling about?
Shirou and I are just, uh...
Right! We're just allies, nothing more!
Oh? Are you now?
What's with that look, like you think you know all about us?
Go on, tell him, Shirou!
S-Say something, you jerk!
I-If you don't, that's as good as saying that we really are a couple.
"Really are," nothing. You two have been an item for ages.
Jeez.
You're in for a bumpy ride, kid.
Well, I already know that Tohsaka's a handful.
I'll tread lightly around her.
But I must say, she's rather amusing to tease.
Surely just chatting with her won't be a problem.
All right. Let's do it your way.
Until Caster is beaten, we'll accept your help.
It's settled, then.
Why, you...
Now I'm mad!
If it's gonna be like this, I'll tear Caster apart all by myself!
Shouldn't you be on guard outside?
I got tired of going through the motions.
Caster's eyes cover the entire area around the church.
My standing watch is pointless.
And you consider that justification to act on your own?
You've already proven quite a headache for Caster.
You needn't be concerned on that count.
She has her watchful eyes on me as well.
If she sees me acting suspiciously,
I'll be dispatched via Command Spell.
If you know that, then why are you here?
You'll be scolded for breaching her trust.
Nah.
I just figured I never had the chance to get to know you.
I don't see how knowing me would be of any benefit to you.
It isn't about standing to gain anything.
It's... how should I put it?
Like a loose end.
Strictly out of curiosity.
I just want to know your reasons, that's all.
Why would a man who isn't a mage...
agree to this indiscriminate killing?
What is there to say?
My circumstances are similar to Emiya Shirou's.
By accident, an outsider like me
came across Caster and became her Master.
You're telling me, you just happened to possess
both the martial arts skills to kill a Servant
and that spirituality of yours?
That's right.
A person, who was by some mistake
raised that way, blended into society...
and, also by some fluke, encountered things like you that do not belong here either.
That is all it amounts to.
In a big city where all sorts of people come together,
indiscriminate killing is an everyday occurrence,
albeit of a different degree.
Pessimistic fatalism...
Is that what lies at the bottom of you?
I'm not pessimistic,
and I've never felt that the future is set in stone.
I only live in the present.
Speaking of my past is pointless.
I lack what you people would call "criteria of right and wrong."
"Letting people live is probably good,
killing people is probably bad."
Even though I know that,
they seem equally valid to me, and I can't judge which is better.
I was someone who was incapable
of telling which was right—good or evil.
However,
I can explain what I truly am.
When I no longer resist killing, I will be evil,
someone no longer fit to remain in human society.
I'm surprised.
I never expected to hear a cold-blooded killer talk about ethics.
Even if I cannot sense what is right,
I can still discuss what is right.
It's the same as a human speaking
of the beauty of the sky,
even though he cannot fly through it.
I am merely a cold-blooded killer,
born without reason and forgotten,
without ever finding his use.
Someone who has fallen between society's cracks.
Just like you people,
I stand removed from the world.
That isn't true.
Magecraft is something that has
been handed down from the past.
It has both history and motives.
Even if it becomes obsolete, even if it dies out,
it is one of the rules that has always existed
behind the scenes of human society.
The teachings of magecraft are inhumane,
but deep down, those who study it
are more human than anyone.
Were that not the case,
the Holy Grail would not have been created.
Mages fight in accordance with their own desires
and for their own personal gain.
And yet...
Kuzuki Souichirou.
You, who have no wish of your own,
are different from the rest of us.
Am I?
I thought I was like you,
but I am the only one who is different?
Still...
I will correct that mistake.
You said that I have no wish to be granted,
...but I do have a wish.
What?
I am someone who was never able to cultivate an identity.
My own desires are indistinct.
As a result—and it's difficult for me to explain why—
I wanted to make that woman's wish come true.
I believe this to be a humane desire.
Caster's wish, eh?
Her goal is to win the Holy Grail for herself—to set herself free.
You accept that?
That is not a wish.
It is a duty to be carried out naturally in the course of her life.
Even though Caster herself seems unaware of it,
she simply wants to go home.
She has never desired freedom.
The decisive battle is almost upon us.
Return to your post, Archer.
If they haven't given up, this will be their final chance.
I agree.
My assumption has been that they will attack at dawn.
I forgot to ask something.
How do you define whether something is "right"?
Let me see.
It must be something that one does not regret,
even if one has erred in one's decision.
I view good and evil as having equal value,
so that is the only evidence of humanity in me that I see as worthwhile.
So, Lancer...
You know what your job is, right?
Yes.
My role is to fight Archer.
If worst comes to worst, I'll also have to deal with Saber,
but keeping them busy won't be a problem.
Caster also has Assassin working for her.
In the absolute worst-case scenario, you may have to face all three.
Yeah, that bastard will be a problem.
If I had my way, I wouldn't face him even one-on-one.
But Assassin won't show up at the church.
How can you be so sure of that?
If Caster won't return to Ryuudou Temple,
wouldn't she call Assassin to her?
Assassin may be a Servant that Caster summoned,
but as a result, he has limitations.
He cannot leave Ryuudou Temple.
But enough about him.
Can you two really defeat Caster by yourselves?
In a straight magic battle, you don't have a chance.
I suppose not.
But if I can face Caster alone, I think I can blindside her.
Ah, I see.
You have something up your sleeve.
Knowing you, I was certain you would come.
So, what little stratagem have you devised?
You aren't the type to make a challenge without a plan in mind.
Yeah.
For starters, I'll take care of you.
I'm surprised.
You made a pact with a new Servant mere days after losing me?
I know I'm not one to talk, but your fickleness is astonishing.
Perhaps leaving you when I did was a good idea.
Something about you always did irritate me,
but you're rotten to the core, aren't you?
Does betrayal rub you the wrong way, Lancer?
I see no other reason for you to take offense on her behalf.
It just pisses me off that there are Servants like you!
Lancer...
You two get inside.
I'll join you once I've dealt with this bastard.
Understood.
But Archer...
Yeah. I'll hold back.
He's gotta survive long enough to get on his
hands and knees and beg you for forgiveness.
Thank you.
I'm glad you were the one who offered to help us.
Man, this has turned into a mess, hasn't it?
What has, Lancer?
It's nothing.
Speaking as someone who wouldn't dream of casually betraying his master,
that little lady is pretty dazzling.
You're so softhearted, Lancer.
Have you heard the saying,
"The grass is always greener on the other side"?
What are you talking about?
Like I'd know anything about that!
Tohsaka?
Let me say this while I have the chance.
There's actually only one of these pendants.
What do you mean?
This is the one that Archer returned to me...
on the day you were stabbed.
I always assumed he'd just retrieved it for me.
That was all I needed to tell you.
Tohsaka...
Let's go.
Yeah.
I didn't come here to abandon something but to retake something.
No matter what you try, you are no match for me.
You have a fatal lack of pride in your sword skills.
I told you, didn't I?
I only choose the option with the highest chance of success.
The Dark Sword Bares Its Fangs
Next Time